About Me

Summary

I'm an experienced .NET web application developer, who has been working in several enterprise applications since 2015, with a fine knowledge of Database Design, Design Patterns, and Object-Oriented Programming.

I have a solid experience in ASP.NET Web Form and ASP.NET MVC technologies, as well as JavaScript, TypeScript, NodeJS, ReactJS, Twitter Bootstrap, Materialize CSS, and responsive web design. I also have knowledge about distributed programming with WCF, Web APIs, and efficient development modals like Agile-Scrum. My English skill is fluent with IELTS 6.0, certificated since April 2016.

Besides the Full-Stack web developer role, I've also been a Team Leader and Scrum Master.

I like to help and learn from other members, good at teamwork and communication. I am also eager to learn and tend to work well within a group.

Personal Details

Full name: Duong Nhat Minh

> Alias: Mike

➤ Job title: *Full Stack Developer*

Email: minhduongnhat@outlook.com

Skype ID: minhdn1102 Mobile: +84 976 716 296 DOB: 11 February 1996

Address: Cau Giay, Hanoi, Vietnam

Skills

Programming Languages Framework & Platforms

- C# .NET, .NET Core
- HTML 5, CSS3, SCSS
- JavaScript
- TypeScript

- Angular 2+ / ReactJS
- NodeJS
- jQuery / Twitter Bootstrap / Materialize CSS / Tailwind CSS
- ASP.NET MVC / Entity Framework / LINQ to SQL / ADO.NET
- ASP.NET Web API / RESTful API/ JSON, XML
- WCF
- ASP.NET Core

Database

- PostgreSQL
- Microsoft SQL Server
- MySQL
- Basic Knowledge of MongoDB

Version Control

Git (GitHub & Gitlab)Team FoundationServer (TFS)

- SVN (Tortoise SVN)

IDE

Visual StudioVisual CodeBrackets

Foreign Language

- TOEIC 750/900 (recorded 2017)
- IELTS 6.0 (recorded April 2016)

Knowledge / Other Skills

- Been a Team Leader and Scrum Master
- Good understanding and familiar with Agile and Scrum process
- Familiar with Unit testing
- Deep understanding about OOP, Design Patterns, SOLID principles, Dependency Injection, ...
- Familiar with Clean Code and Code Refactoring
- Good understanding about software design, database design, system design, Restful API
- Good time management, presentation, and teamwork skills

Experiences

Career Summary

- Working with .NET projects for enterprise since 2015.
- Have strong knowledge of web-based applications, software design, Windows Service, and Web API.
- Experienced with NodeJS and None-Microsoft systems.
- Fluent in English communication IELTS 6.0 since April 2016.
- Familiar with Agile, and Scum projects.
- Working on many OSDC projects. Working directly with customers.

Employment History – Work Experiences

Ascentis	
Position: Scrum Master / Full Stack Developer	
Duration: March 2020 – Present	
Company: Ascentis	
Team Size: Multiple Teams, 2 to 7 members each team	
Description	Ascentis is one of the top companies that specialize in providing CRM – CMS solutions integrated with Ecommerce. The company has a vast number of clients in the eCommerce industry. I've been working for Ascentis since March 2020.
Responsibilities	I have had a chance to work on multiple projects for multiple clients. For most of my time here I was designated to the BAU team. The purpose of this team is to maintain and execute the change requests for a large number of projects from the clients of Ascentis.

I was the Full-Stack web developer and Scrum Master for this team. During my time here, my responsibilities are: Step by step, sprint by sprint, to build the Scrum process for the team, so that the process is there to help the team work effectively, not blocking their way Make sure the process is reasonable and well-adapted by other team members Make sure all members understand the process and comfortable while following that process Make sure the team is proactive in getting advice/explanation about the task assigned Helping team members to resolve blockers Code review Fix bugs, implement updates, or change requests Deploy to UAT to verify, request for deployment on Production, and verify Working with BA, developers, PO, and testers from other teams, make sure the changes are implemented correctly as the requirements and work smoothly, not break any other business after released Asp.NET Web Form **Project Technologies** Asp.NET MVC .NET Core / .NET 6 HTML, CSS, SCSS, jQuery, JavaScript, TypeScript ReactJS NodeJS Team Foundation Server (TFS) with CI/CD SQL Server PostgreSQL Hangfire **Orchard Core**

4.00		
A Startup for E-Commerce and payment solutions		
Position: Team Lead / Full Stack Developer Duration: August 2019 – March 2020 Company: ITE		
Team Size: 8 members		
Description	The company is a startup company, focused on building product applications, with the business domain is about handling the payment process for e-commerce websites. The company's business strategy is to aim to the e-commerce enterprises in need of integrating online payment methods.	
	During my short time working here, I was both a team leader and the main front-end developer. I was also working on multiple projects at a time.	
	 I have gone through three projects here, which are: a Landing Page working as a gateway to routing customers to the payment gateway of the payment type they choose an Admin Management System that allows the administrators to manage the customers' information, their transactions, the sales information, 	
	They are all built using Angular 8, Angular Material, some other libraries for front-end. For the back-end, we used .Netcore Web API / Java Web API or NodeJS.	
Responsibilities	My responsibilities and what I have done during the time I worked here are: - Help BA to design mockup UI	
	- Help BA to clarify and build requirements	
	- Design a working process for everybody	
	- Design business flow and user behavior for the products	
	- Involved in the process of designing and improving API	
	- Main front-end developer	
	- Mentor new members	
	- Support other members	
	- Review code	
	- Build and set up servers for the products	
	- Merge code and deploy products to servers	
Project Technologies	ReactJS Angular 8	
	Angular Material	
	Twitter Bootstrap	
	Entities Framework	
	NGINX	

NodeJS
.Net Core web API
Microsoft SQL Server
JAVA
MySQL

Top UK's Recruiter Company - Reed

Position: Full stack developer

Duration: June 2018 – August 2019 Company: Harvey Nash Viet Nam

Team Size: 22 members

Description

For a long time, since 1995, the company has been the best recruiter platform in the United Kingdom. Now they are still one of the best. The company provides a service that connects both the recruiters and

the people looking for a job in the most efficient way.

Been running for a long time, the old service is no longer catching up

Been running for a long time, the old service is no longer catching up with the latest technologies and the latest business domains, therefore no longer able to provide the best service for their customers.

A development team is founded to help improve the company's service to be more efficient and able to match the latest requirements of the new era. The new development team has 20+ members with 2 subteams:

- Recruiter: handling the business for the recruiter to find proper, relevant, and suitable candidates
- <u>Jobseeker</u>: handling the business that allows the people to find the correct jobs and companies that they are looking for

Responsibilities

As one of the experienced developers with fluent English communication skills, I was put into the Jobseeker team to handle the core business domain directly with the customer.

- Communicate with the customer to get clear requirements
- Breakdown customer's requirements into tickets and sub-tasks
- Refinement and planning for sprints
- Update code according to the ticket's requirements, for the tickets which are assigned to me
- Help and support other team members with their tickets, and communication with the customer
- Perform unit testing
- Frequently reviewing tickets are done by other team members

	ASP.NET MVC
Project Technologies	ReactJS, Knockout JS, HTML, CSS, Twitter Bootstrap
	Dapper, NHibernate
	Entities Framework
	Web APIs
	SQL SERVER
	Design patterns (DI/IoC, MVC,)
	CI/CD (TeamCity)

Sitecore Team for an Airline Corporation - Vietnam Airline		
Position: Backend developer		
Duration: January 2018 - May 2018		
Company: FPT Software - FSU1.BU9		
Team Size: 5 members		
	The customer is one of the biggest airlines in Vietnam and they are in	
Description	need of updating their services to be more efficient, the development	
	team is founded to help on updating the technologies on the	
	customer's services so that these can operate more properly and more	
	efficiently.	
	- Study Functional Design Specification	
Responsibilities	 Produce Technical Design Specifications, Design Input 	
	- Creating UI with Sitecore and MVC	
	- Coding Web API	
	 Update and manage stored procedures 	
	- Coding Unit Test	
	 Site Core for ASP.NET Webform and ASP.NET for MVC 	
Project Technologies	- ASP.NET MVC	
	- ASP.NET Webform	
	- Entities Framework	
	- Web APIs	
	- SQL Server	
	- HTML5 – CSS3	
	- JavaScript - JQuery	

Sitecore Team for an Energy Provider Corporation - Innogy

Position: Full stack developer

Duration: June 2017 - December 2017 Company: FPT Software - FSU1.BU9

Team Size: 6 members

	The customer is one of the greatest energy corporations in the world. It
Description	is the main energy provider for all countries in Europe. The team is born
	to help the customer to manage their websites to:
	- Increase their client's range
	 Provide a better and more efficient way for the clients to
	approach their services and products
	- Allow the customer to easily control and maintain their
	websites
	- Allow the customer to have better knowledge about their
	clients (statistic reports)
	- Study Functional Design Specification
Responsibilities	- Produce Technical Design Specifications, Design Input
	- Creating UI with Sitecore and MVC
	- Coding Web API
	 Update and manage stored procedures
	- Coding Unit Test
	- Site Core for ASP.NET MVC
Project Technologies	- ASP.NET MVC
	- Entities Framework
	- Web APIs
	- SQL Server
	- HTML5 – CSS3
	- JavaScript - jQuery

Top Singa	pore's Customs - Cargo Community Network (CCN)
Position: Junior to Full Stack	Developer
Duration: October 2015 - Jur	ne 2017
Company: FPT Software - FSI	J1.BU1
Team Size: 8 members	
	The customer is a Singapore company that provides cargo shipment
Description	and management systems for the air cargo industry. Their service is
	used by many Customs around the world.
	Their service allows customers to:
	- Easily connect to all supply chain stakeholders
	- Access to comprehensive portfolios of advanced IT solution
	- Simplify the work in cargo management (shipment details,
	shipment status,)
	- Efficient in customs security compliance
	- Business performance analytics
	- Study Functional Design Specification

Responsibilities	- Produce Technical Design Specifications, Design Input
	- Coding Web API
	- Coding WCF service
	- Coding business logic
	- Create store procedures
	 Coding Unit test scripts and integrating modules
	- C# .NET
Project Technologies	- ASP.NET Webform
	- Team Foundation Server 2012
	- Azure Service Bus
	- HTML, Twitter Bootstrap, Telerik
	- JavaScript, Query
	- SQL Server 2012, 2014
	- XAML, XML

EDUCATION

2016 – 2018: University of Greenwich – Computer Engineering Education Programme



2013 - 2015: Aptech - Higher Diploma in Software Engineering